First, open the Modelist Designer, then import Hanna, then switch Hanna's surface type to black and white surface
Then we are going to start making the skirt
The basis of making the skirt is the belt
We need to make the belt first, and then create other plates with the size of the belt
So here we are going to draw a rectangle
This rectangle is about 2.5 times the width of our waist to 3 times the width
Then press Ctrl D to create a symmetrical plate
Press Shift F to open the arrangement point and arrange the plate on both sides
Now this plate is a certain distance from the body
So here we use the ruler to arrange the ruler here at the bottom
Bring the plate closer to the model
This can avoid penetration
Then use the Hanna tool to click and sew the two sides together
After sewing, press Ctrl G to simulate
After the simulation, we need to adjust the belt to the appropriate length
When making the belt, we usually make it into a tight, tight state
So we need to lower the model's surface ruler first
So that the plate can be closer to the body
Next, we are going to change the belt to a tight state
Because now this belt can be seen to be very loose
Note that we are going to be tight, not tight
So we can modify it little by little
Next to the display clothing type, there is a hard drive
We can open the hard drive to see the color of the grid
The color is from blue to red
If it's yellow green, it means it's a little tight
So we might want to widen this belt
Make it look like it's blue overall
Once we have confirmed that the width of the belt is just
After we are attached
We can reduce the body diameter of the belt to 10
Then the collision thickness reduces to 1
Collision thickness is the air thickness surrounding the plate
We can also reduce the width to 0.5-2.7mm
Will reduce the air thickness of the plate to 1.8-1.8mm
to make it a little closer to the body
Then we can switch back to the skin surface
to see if its location is reasonable
Then we can switch back to the black and white surface
Then we can cancel this pressure map
Next we are going to start making the butt
Because people are actually three-dimensional
It's not as big as a scissor
The person has a side thickness
There is some width of the butt
So we need to pay attention when we are drawing a multidimensional
Because the back piece will be copied to another version later
So here we only draw half the length of the waist
In the process of drawing, press the ESC key
You can cancel the position and start drawing again
Because later we are going to refer to the scissor in the 2D window
to draw
this
So in the 2D window
First arrange the belt in the corresponding position with 3D
Then draw half of the waist first
Then we press the control key
Create the rest of the curve points
The whole side curve
We can't all use curve points to draw
But it needs to be in some fixed positions
Hit the breakpoint
That is to say, release the control key
To create some straight lines
Press the return key
You can return to the location of the previous point
So how do we hit the breakpoint?
We usually choose a few special positions
One is the widest part of the hip
That is, the position of our hip
And the other is the widest part of our thigh
Because the hip has a curve
So don't create a straight line here
It's best to add a curve in the middle
Then to the widest position of the hip
Loosen the control key
Click to create a straight line
Then we can continue to create the thigh
The widest point of the thigh
And the knee point of the thigh
Then when you select this plate
Press the control key
Create a symmetrical plate
Then select at the same time
Copy and paste to the side
Then when you select the copied plate
Arrange it in the middle of the back
Arrange the front in the front
After completion
Press Shift F to hide the arrangement point
Then we can slightly adjust its position
Adjust them to the belt below
Then we freeze the belt plate
Then use the line sewing tool
First click on the longest belt side
Then press the Shift key
Gradually click on the side with its sewing
Then release the Shift key
Other positions can be according to their own habits
Use the line sewing tool to separate them
Then press the control key to simulate
Now the basic model of the bag skirt is ready
Next we need to adjust its size of some details
Now we can open the pressure map and look at it
Here we can see
There will be a large red part at the back
Or the orange part
That means it's tight
The whole front looks okay
The reason why this happens is because
The model's butt is relatively plump
The basis of our creation is the side shadow of the front
So next we need to select the whole side
Take it out
Pull it a little bit
This will add more fabric to the back
You can move it while pressing the control key
Open the simulation
To see if it's too loose or too tight in the 3D space
Here we just move its side line
Because we want to make sure that its side curve is the same
If the curve is not the same
It's easy to have some ugly wrinkles
Because now we're going to say
It's the waist line that's been widened
So there's going to be some wrinkles here
So now we're going to take the back of the skirt
This line at the top here
To dig out a part
When you use the editor to select this line
We can see the difference between the two ends
The difference here is 30 mm
So I press the X key
Add a point first
Right click to select add
The line will dig out a triangular area
Here we set the width to 30
Because we didn't adjust the line before
So use the editor to delete this circle of the line
And then re-create it
After we open the simulation
You'll see that most of the red areas have disappeared
And part of it is because we didn't untie the belt
So here we can untie or activate this belt plate
And then simulate it
In the 3D window, you can see that
After we dug out the triangle
The point of the triangle is a little bit obvious
Then we can move this point of the triangle down
Move it to almost the widest position of the hip
A little bit above
This way, the width of our entire belt
Will be a little bit more natural
After opening the simulation
There will be no obvious point of the triangle
Showed out
The principle is also very simple
You can imagine
The person must be the thinnest in the waist
The widest in the hip
So we add this triangle
The area of ​​the triangle
Is also the most of the waist
The least of the hip
Just now I have switched to the transparency picture
The shortcut to the transparency picture is Alt4
We won't change the belt here
So let's freeze the belt first
Next, we're going to start modifying the side of this plate
First, we can based on this transparency picture
Click on the plate
You can see that there is a blue dot between the 3D and 2D windows at the same time
This blue dot is convenient for us to go through
To locate
So in the process of clicking just now
Will find
Near the blue dot
The curve here is not suitable for the human body
So we're going to use the editor curve point tool
Drag this point in
You can see
When I'm modifying this curve point
It won't affect the bottom
So we can modify it
Just press the control key to simulate
Here we can find the benefits of segment modification
Segment modification
You won't affect other places
Then here
If we move this straight point
It will still affect other plates
So what we're going to do
Is to use the circular curve tool
Make a angle for the corner here
When you make the angle of the back and forth
You have to pay attention to try to make them the same
And then we can continue to use this kind of protruding place
Whether it's the edge curve point
Or the edge circle tool
To drag this line
Or adjust the curve point above
All right
If we want to modify the area is relatively small
We can add two points on both sides
To prevent it from affecting other lines
Then you can choose to turn the middle point into a curve point
So that it won't be so deep
Then you can also move this straight point according to the need
Or to change its curve
And then if there's still a protruding place
We can move the straight point
Let it look as smooth as possible
Smooth curve line
Finally, after determining the overall curve line
We can turn these straight points into curve points
Unless we have to make other adjustments to it later
Otherwise, we will basically turn it into a curve point in the last step
Segment modification
After turning it into a curve point
You will see that it is very smooth
Then we can fix it according to the method just now
This point below
You can see that it is very smooth
And then we can turn it into a curve point
And then we can fix it according to the method just now
Then some children may ask
Why are we using the curve point here
Instead of deleting these two straight points directly
Because the straight point will control other curve points
If you delete these two points
If you delete the straight point above
Then there will be a default straight line in the middle
The previous curve points will be gone
So here we are going to use the free curve point
Now the whole thing looks like a bagging group
If we say we want it to be a group
Then we usually pull the bottom point out
To adjust it separately
This is a group of a
You can save it after you're done
Next, let's make this bagging group a little bit tighter
First of all, we need to merge the front and the middle
Because it's a complete board
The back and middle are the same
Now, if we just drag this board directly
It can't form a very obvious fold
Because it's overall still relatively fast
It's a state of Teams
So now we need to get it adjusted a little tighter
Here we look at
If we take care of its side
Because the waist is tight here
So if we're dragging the board again
It's easy to form some pile of fold wrinkles in the waist
Well, what we want to know is
We want to control the location of the fold wrinkles
For example, I want to control it in the back side
If it only appears in the leg, it will not reach the abdomen,
then we only move from the widest position of the thigh to the lower line.
After adjustment, open the simulation.
After that, we will drag the plate during the simulation process,
it can be well fixed in the widest position of the thigh.
After the fabric is raised, if there is a problem with the protruding foot on its side,
we will put the points on both sides in a little bit.
After the simulation, if it falls down, we can continue to repeat these steps,
while looking at the simulation, while dragging these plates.
If the skirt is a little longer, we can drag the bottom plate up this side.
Now the folds are relatively large and deep,
because our particle diameter is 20.
So next we need to adjust the particle diameter,
reduce it to 10, reduce the conflict thickness to 1.
The mechanism is also the same,
this is also a step before repetition,
when looking at the simulation, drag the whole piece.
If you feel that the number of folds in the shape is not enough,
then we can put its fascia strength here,
and the angle strength is increased a little bit,
the angle strength is increased a little bit.
In this way, the stretch performance of our fabric will become worse,
and it is easier to produce some folds.
In fact, because we are now talking about the skirt,
it is a fold that forms a fold,
so there will inevitably be some traces of folds on the side.
If you want to slightly erase this part of the fold,
we are going to use the龜拔 here.
When the龜拔 is shrinked to a negative value,
this part of the grid will shrink.
So we can adjust the size a little bit,
and also adjust its width a little bit.
Then click and drag the mouse on this side
to create a shrinked position.
In places where there are more folds,
we can click a few more times.
After the fold is probably flattened,
if there is a little bit of a small fold,
we can drag the fabric to flatten it.
In this way, a very tight skirt is done.
We can freeze this board first,
and then use it later.
Next, let's add a river side to it.
Draw a rectangular board.
This rectangular board is longer than the two boards on one side.
Because we are going to create a symmetrical board later,
so it just needs to be longer than the two boards on one side.
Then press Ctrl D to create a symmetrical board.
Then use the line sewing tool to sew them together.
During the sewing process, remember to press the Shift key first,
and select the long section first.
Then press the Shift key to remove it.
Here we must pay attention to not directly simulate.
Because if we directly simulate,
because there is a board that is worn from the front to the back,
it may be unstable.
So in 3D space,
we need to adjust it to the side of the virtual model first,
then simulate.
We can see that these sewing lines
are almost evenly distributed.
Then simulate.
Do not simulate directly in the front.
After simulating,
we can drag the board to make it more flat.
Then use the line sewing tool to sew the sides together.
Summary
Also the same.
Reduce the thickness of the particle diameter to 10.
Reduce the thickness of the collision to 1.
In fact, the main reason is that
when our particle diameter is large,
when the number is small,
its curve is not very even.
Like this, a smaller board,
we can also reduce its particle diameter to 8
Now the whole group looks a little chubby
Then we can continue to make some adjustments to its properties
First we want to copy this fabric
Then drag this fabric to the bottom of these two panels
Then reduce their fine-tuning strength and focus strength a little
Under such adjustments
Because the fabric itself becomes easy to stretch and tighten
At the same time, its heat retention is better
So it looks a little softer
Then we can reduce the bending strength a little more
So that it looks softer
After we adjust it
We can reduce the particle diameter to 5
So that we can see its smoother and smoother effect
Then we can reduce the deformation strength of the fabric a little more
The deformation strength is to control the strength of the wrinkles that have been formed
This value is actually the percentage of the fine-tuning
That is to say, if it is 30
It is 30% bend strength
Of course, it has a premise that it is a wrinkle that has been formed
Then we can activate other panels
Simulate with this panel
Then you can adjust these details according to your needs
If you want to make an open fork
It's also very convenient
Directly use the edge sewing line tool
Delete this sewing line at the end
Or the top of the moving sewing line
That's it
This is the end of this video
Thank you for watching
See you in the next video
Bye bye